Your son
Сын
Understands
понял
Good
Хорошо
This Chu Huan is a loyal and righteous man
Этот Чу Хуань верный и преданный человек
Before he goes
Перед отъездом
Go see him
навести его
Yes
Ваше Высочество
You've come
вы пришли
Before acting
Ещё до начала дела
Your subject thought he might lose his head
я знал что могу лишиться головы
Just didn't think
Только не ожидал
It would nearly drag Your Highness down
что подставлю и вас
Chu Huan
Чу Хуань
The order was mine
приказ отдал я
You've followed me since the north
Ты следовал за мной с самого севера
I
я
Your subject first followed Your Highness
Поначалу я следовал за Вашим Высочеством
Only for the prince's salary
лишь получая жалованье
Following Your Highness south
Когда пошёл на юг с вами
Was to preserve life and body
берёг себя и свою жизнь
Now your subject
Теперь же я
Is guilty before heaven's might
виновен перед Небесной волей
Guilty before the times
виновен перед временем
Why does Your Highness blame yourself?
За что Вы себя вините
The high noble families
Знатные роды
Are the mountains connecting all of Jiangnan
это горы что протянулись по всему югу
Both protecting the current Xuan Kingdom
Они и защищают нынешнюю Сюань
And keeping the Son of Heaven
но и не дают императору
From leaving their shadow
выбраться из их тени
Your subject
Я
Since I cannot be
раз не могу стать
The blade that splits mountains
мечом что рассекает горы
Then to be Your Highness's
то стать для Вашего Высочества
Stepping stone
кирпичом под ногами
Is fine
тоже хорошо
When we went south
Когда мы шли на юг
Your subject had family and old friends
у меня остались родные и друзья
Left in the north
на севере
Under your subject
Среди моих людей
Are many people
много
Like your subject
таких же
Your Highness once promised me
Вы обещали мне
Them
им
And the millions of northern people
и миллионам бывших жителей севера
That one day
однажды
We would defeat the Wutu in the north
мы отвоюем земли у варваров
And recover our land
и вернём наши горы и реки
Is there anything else
Есть ли ещё чтото
You need me to do?
что мне нужно для тебя сделать
Your subject has a capable student
У меня есть способный ученик
Named Zhu Yuanzhi
его зовут Чжу Юаньчжи
Please, Your Highness
Прошу вас Ваше Высочество
Put him to good use
дать ему шанс
Certainly
Обязательно
This half journey
На этом пути
To be able to serve Your Highness
быть для Вашего Высочества
Shelter from wind and rain
защитой от бури
And block blades
щитом от мечей
Is Huan's fortune
это счастье для Хуаня
This cup of wine
Этой прощальной чаши вина
Your subject
я
Deserves
достоин
To Your Highness
За Ваше Высочество